Cole Johnson

Full Stack Developer

541-588-2911 | cburnjohnson@gmail.com | Beaverton, OR 97006

Portfolio: cburnjohnson | linkedin.com/in/cburnjohnson/

PROFILE

I am a passionate Full Stack Developer with industry experience building web applications using Agile methodologies. The stack I enjoy the most developing with is the MERN stack. I love the flexibility of JavaScript, but my passion for development doesn't stem from one language or stack. My passion comes from the immense amount of learning opportunities that arise each project I start.

SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Python, C#, C, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS, Sass/SCSS.

Frameworks/Libraries: React, Node, Express, Redux, Gastby, .NET, Django, Bootstrap, Materialize.

Databases: MongoDB, SQL Server, MySQL.

Version Control: Git, Azure DevOps.

Technical: REST APIs, SASS.

Methodologies/Design: Agile, Scrum, Model-View-Controller

General: Problem Solving, Project Management, Microsoft Office, Critical Thinking, Time Management,

Adaptability, Attention to Detail, Self-Motivated.

PROJECTS

Watch N Track - MERN Full Stack Application - https://watchntrack.herokuapp.com/

Technology Used: React, Node, MongoDB, Express, JavaScript, CSS.

- Application that allows the user to track movies, TV shows, and anime they have watched.
- Back end REST API created with Node and Express library.
- Implemented the mongoose library to connect to MongoDB, and create database schemas/models.
- User registration/login system with validation and authentication.
 - JSON web tokens are used for user authentication.
- Users are able to filter through their tracked movies, TV shows, and anime, as well as add, delete, edit, or update them.

Phone Book - MERN Full Stack Application - https://phonebook47.herokuapp.com/

Technology Used: React. Node. MongoDB. Express. JavaScript. CSS.

- Application that stores the user's personal/professional contacts built with the MERN stack.
- Complete registration and login system with validation.
 - Implemented JSON Web Tokens to help with authentication.
- Back end API created with Express, supports CRUD functionalities for contacts.
- Authenticated users are able to filter through contacts, as well as add, delete, edit, or update contacts.

Where To Eat - React Front End Application - https://wheretoeat.netlify.com/

Technology Used: React, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, Google Places API.

- React application that displays randomized nearby restaurants.
 - Consumes Google Places API to collect restaurant information.
- A single restaurant's name, picture, address, phone number, website, price, rating, and total reviews
 are displayed inside a container with the ability to pass on the current restaurant.
 - Pass functionality removes the current displayed restaurant and replaces it with a new random restaurant.
- The front end was built using the CSS framework Bootstrap, and custom CSS.

<u>LoL Summoners</u> - React Front End Application - https://lolsummoners.netlify.com/

Technology Used: React, JavaScript, CSS.

• Application that lets users look up their League of Legends account information.

- Displays the searched account summoner level, summoner icon, queue ranks, and recent match history.
 - o Consumes Riot Game's League, Match, and Summoner APIs.
- Implemented React's Context API to manage the application's state easier.
- Uses React-Router to help with state when redirecting from the homepage to the account details page.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Prosper I.T. Consulting, Portland, OR. - Intern Software Developer

March 2019 - June 2019

- Contributed towards developing a C#/Asp.net Construction Management web application.
 - Back end: Implemented the user creation system, and populating the database with initial seed data for testing.
 - Front end: Created the user creation page, and navigation bar.
 - Project summary: https://github.com/cburnjohnson/Construction-Management-System
- Worked with a team developing a Python/Django web application that utilizes data scraping, and REST APIs to produce sub applications that run on the overall project.
 - Back end: Developed the Directions application, Messaging application, and User Creation.
 - Front end: Built the Directions application page.
 - Project summary: https://github.com/cburnjohnson/Data-Scrape 3-25
- Utilized Agile methodology Scrum for workflow and project management to increase team productivity.
 - Attended daily stand-up meetings with the development team to coordinate project priorities.
- Trained under a Senior Developer that mentored me to become proficient working on the front end, and back end.

Candy Tyme, Eugene, OR - Assistant Manager

September 2017 - November 2018

- Trained all newly hired employees on day to day tasks at the store.
 - Coached employees on upselling techniques to improve overall sales of the store.
- Implemented employee of the month system based on employee sales to improve team morale.
- Performed weekly inventory counts, and supply orders for needed products.
- Responsible for handling money, and completing money drops at the bank.
- Participated in conference calls with the other Candy Tyme store managers, and owner of the stores.

Subway, Bend, OR - Shift Manager

October 2016 - August 2017

- Became the main closer for the store, and was assigned to train employees on closing duties.
- Solved any problems that came up during my shift which included customer, team members, and shipment problems.
- Happily cooperated with team members to construct sandwiches efficiently.
 - Designated team members to specific stations to help with organization during rush hours.

EDUCATION

The Tech Academy, Portland, OR. - Software Developer Certificate

November 2018 - May 2019

The Tech Academy is an intensive software developer boot camp that has over 600 hours of hands-on learning. I learned the fundamentals of software development, as well as the most common web development languages, and frameworks. Some of the languages, and frameworks I learned are C#, Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Django, Bootstrap, and .NET.

Central Oregon Community College, Bend, OR. - Associate of Science

September 2014 - June 2016

Completed a variety of courses during my time at this institute that included Anthropology, Psychology, Calculus, and Computer Science. Associate of Science in Chemistry.